<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slides on Julien Pascal</title>
    <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slides on Julien Pascal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Julien Pascal</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rental Housing Market and Directed Search</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/rental-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/rental-market/</guid>
      <description>Rental Housing Market and Directed Search Introduction Context  Rents have surged in big cities worldwide   The median American rent payment rose 61% in real terms between 1960 and 2016 while the median renter’s income grew by 5%
  Housing shortages and rent control in many major cities  Questions  Are rent control legislations effective? Do we observe asymmetric bargaining power between renters and landlords?  Data Data Sources  Web scraping: online ads posted on the major platforms for the Paris market (PAP, Leboncoin, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Equilibrium and Commuting Costs</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/spatial-eq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/spatial-eq/</guid>
      <description>Spatial Equilibrium and Commuting Costs Introduction  The &amp;ldquo;Forfait Toutes Zones&amp;rdquo; (FTZ) entered into force on September 2015 in the Paris area The costs of using public transports decreased for workers living in the outskirts of Paris (zones 3-5) Using the spatial discontinuity generated by the reform, I analyze the links between commuting costs and local employment outcomes  Data Data Sources  Monthly # of workers registered to Pole Emploi at the municipality level: Pole Emploi Demographic and economic characteristics of municipalities and IRIS: INSEE House price index at the municipality level: Chambre des Notaires de Paris Fare area at the IRIS level: Vianavigo Behavior of travelers on the public transport network: STIF  Cost change by fare area Average cost difference by fare area Fare area at the IRIS level Econometrics Main specification $$y_{it} = \alpha_i + \gamma_t + \beta \times \delta_{i,t} + \boldsymbol{\eta} \boldsymbol{x_{i,t}}^{&amp;lsquo;} + \varepsilon_{i,t}$$</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>