<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slides on Julien Pascal</title>
    <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slides on Julien Pascal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Julien Pascal</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A crash course on Git and Gitlab</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/intro_git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/intro_git/</guid>
      <description>A crash course on Git and Gitlab What? Version control
 version control (also known as revision control, source control, or source code management) is a class of systems responsible for managing changes to computer programs, documents, large web sites, or other collections of information.
 source: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Version_control
Why? (1&amp;frasl;2) Other people are using Git (network effect)
Notes: Open source repositories registered on Ohloh Source
Why? (2&amp;frasl;2) Advantages  Keep an organized history of a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A crash course on Git and Gitlab</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/intro_git_local/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/intro_git_local/</guid>
      <description>A crash course on Git and Gitlab What? Version control
 version control (also known as revision control, source control, or source code management) is a class of systems responsible for managing changes to computer programs, documents, large web sites, or other collections of information.
 source: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Version_control
Why? Advantages  Keep an organized history of a project. No more:   Easy to collaborate: working simultaneously with the same file(s)  How?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capstone Project - The Battle of Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/neighbourhoods_paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/neighbourhoods_paris/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Which neighborhoods to visit when in Paris? Where to live in Paris?  Answers depend on your preferences
This project  Cluster neighborhoods in Paris and analyze cluster properties  Data and Methodology Data Sources  Foursquare: geolocalized data on venues Wikipedia: data on neighborhoods (called &amp;ldquo;arrondissements&amp;rdquo;)  Methodology  Similarity based on venue types (restaurants, cafés, hotels, etc.) k-means clustering using scikit-learn  Results Five clusters identified Five clusters identified  cluster 1 (in red): 5th, 7th, 8th, 14th, 15th, 16th and 17th arrondissements cluster 2 (in purple): 12th arrondissement cluster 3 (in blue): 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 6th, 9th and 10th cluster 4 (in light green): 11th, 18th, 19th, and 20th cluster 5 (in orange): 13th arrondissement  Cluster properties Cluster 1 Cluster 2 Cluster 3 Cluster 4 Cluster 5 Suggestions based on preferences  cluster 1: for a “French” experience, in a mostly quiet and residential area cluster 2: for fresh air and sport (near the Bois de Vincennes) cluster 3: a mix of art, museums and diverse cuisine cluster 4: for the best bars and pizza experience in town cluster 5: Asian cuisine aficionados  Conclusion  Which neighborhoods to visit when in Paris?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Econometrics II: Lecture I OLS</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/lectures-econo-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/lectures-econo-2-1/</guid>
      <description>Econometrics II Lecture I - OLS Introduction Motivation  Econometrics is the science of making causal statements using both theory and data Constraints: the world is probabilistic, the data we have is messy, theories are incomplete, etc&amp;hellip; We have to take these constraints into consideration  Looks causal Obvious spurious correlation Looks causal, but careful (see the lecture on Instrumental Variables ) The Linear Model  A building block to model and assess causality is the linear model  $$ y = X \beta + \varepsilon $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rental Housing Market and Directed Search</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/rental-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/rental-market/</guid>
      <description>Rental Housing Market and Directed Search Introduction Context  Housing shortages in many major cities Rents have surged in big cities worldwide   The median American rent payment rose 61% in real terms between 1960 and 2016 while the median tenant’s income grew by 5%
 Rents have outpaced household disposable income in Paris Questions  Do we observe asymmetric bargaining power between tenants and landlords?  Data Data Sources  Web scraping: online platform that collects online ads for the Paris market between April and May 2019 I have data on the two sides of the rental housing market:  supply: apartment features, text description and photos demand: number of contacts received by landlords (through the online platform)   Descriptive statistics Ads per city Apartment features Apartment features by city Population (2017) Number of ads Median rent per m² Aesthetic score  Aesthetic score calculated based on photos I use a convolutional neural network (CNN) based on the work of Talebi and Milanfar (2018) CNN assigns a score to each photo Ad aesthetic score = median score  Number of photos per ad Density aesthetic score Selected sample of photos in the top 1% Selected sample of photos in the bottom 1% What features are important to predict rent?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Equilibrium and Commuting Costs</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/spatial-eq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/slides/spatial-eq/</guid>
      <description>Spatial Equilibrium and Commuting Costs Introduction  The &amp;ldquo;Forfait Toutes Zones&amp;rdquo; (FTZ) entered into force on September 2015 in the Paris area The costs of using public transports decreased for workers living in the outskirts of Paris (zones 3-5) Using the spatial discontinuity generated by the reform, I analyze the links between commuting costs and local employment outcomes  Context: Grand Paris Express source: https://www.societedugrandparis.fr/gpe/carte#lignes
Context: Grand Paris Express source: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>