<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Julien Pascal</title>
    <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Julien Pascal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Julien Pascal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://julienpascal.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a PhD candidate in Economics at Sciences Po - LIEPP under the supervision of Jean-Marc Robin.
My research focuses on heterogeneous agents models and frictional markets. I am also interested in efficiency analysis and applied asset pricing. Prior to starting my PhD, I worked at the Economics Department of the OECD. You can find my resume here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description> 2017-2018 Econometrics II (graduate)  Lecturer: Jean-Marc Robin, Professor Sciences Po and UCL Content: OLS, GLS, IV, qualitative response models, limited dependent variables, Stata  Applied Statistics for Business and Economics (graduate)  Lecturer: Matteo Mogliani, Senior Economist at the Banque de France Content: introduction to probability theory and regression analysis with a focus on applications in finance and economics  Previous Teaching Positions 2016-2017 Money and Banking (undergraduate)  Lecturer: Johannes Boehm, Assistant Professor Sciences Po Content: inter-temporal consumption and saving decisions, quantity theory of money, neo-keynesian models, central bank&amp;rsquo;s inflation bias, commitment vs discretion in monetary policy, bank runs  Introduction to Econometrics and Statistics (graduate)  Lecturer: Matteo Mogliani, Senior Economist at the Banque de France Content: introduction to probability theory, univariate and multivariate regression models, inference and hypothesis testing  Econometrics II (graduate)  Lecturer: Jean-Marc Robin, Professor Sciences Po and UCL Content: OLS, GLS, IV, qualitative response models, limited dependent variables  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>