<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Julien Pascal</title>
    <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Julien Pascal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Julien Pascal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 18:11:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://julienpascal.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rental Housing Market and Directed Search</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/rentalmarket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/rentalmarket/</guid>
      <description>This paper introduces new empirical findings concerning the functioning of the rental housing market. Utilizing a unique dataset gathered from online advertisements for Parisian rentals, along with a hedonic model that incorporates both apartment features and property-specific photographs, two main stylized facts are established. First, landlords who offer lower rent, while keeping property features constant, attract a greater number of applicants, consistent with predictions from standard directed search models. Second, a previously unreported trend in landlords&amp;rsquo; pricing strategies is identified: a significant portion employ a two-stage pricing approach, initially setting a high advertised rent and subsequently reducing it after a &amp;ldquo;wait-and-see&amp;rdquo; period, consistent with the slow Dutch auction mechanism already studied in the auction literature and empirically observed in the property sales market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Equilibrium and Commuting Costs</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/spatialeq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/spatialeq/</guid>
      <description>This paper explores the connection between commuting costs and local employment dynamics, exploiting a spatial discontinuity introduced by a reform in France in September 2015. The reform, which reduced the cost of public transportation in selected areas of the Paris region without affecting others, provides a unique opportunity to investigate these dynamics. Using a baseline regression framework that only includes geographical units near each other, I find that areas benefitting from the reform saw a 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Income Shocks Along the Business Cycle</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/laborincomeshocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/laborincomeshocks/</guid>
      <description>This paper analyzes the determinants of labor income shocks along the business cycle. My main finding is that sorting between firms and workers is a key component of idiosyncratic risk. Labor income shocks are analyzed through the lenses of a dynamic search-and-matching model, which I estimate using US data. Because of search frictions and mismatches between firms and workers, the laissez-faire equilibrium is not necessarily optimal. My results underline that the government can tame business cycle fluctuations by designing a simple unemployment insurance scheme improving sorting between firms and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>