<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Julien Pascal</title>
    <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Julien Pascal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Julien Pascal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 18:11:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://julienpascal.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Neural Networks to solve dynamic programming problems: a bias-corrected Monte Carlo operator</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/ann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/ann/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) are powerful tools that can solve dynamic programming problems arising in economics. In this context, estimating ANN parameters involves minimizing a loss function based on the model’s stochastic functional equations. In general, the expectations appearing in the loss function admit no closed-form solution, so numerical approximation techniques must be used. In this paper, I analyze a bias-corrected Monte Carlo operator (bc-MC) that approximates expectations by Monte Carlo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(In)efficient commuting and migration choices</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/inefficient_commuting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/inefficient_commuting/</guid>
      <description>We develop a monocentric urban search-and-matching model in which workers can choose to commute or to migrate within the region. The equilibrium endogenously allocates the population into three categories: migrants (relocate from their hometown to the city), commuters (traveling to work in the city) and home stayers (remaining in their hometown). We prove that the market equilibrium is usually not optimal: a composition externality may generate under- or over-migration with respect to the central planner’s solution, which in all cases results in under-investment in job vacancies and therefore production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rental Housing Market and Directed Search</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/rentalmarket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/rentalmarket/</guid>
      <description>Using a novel dataset on the rental housing market in the Paris area, I show that the rental housing market is well described by a directed search model. I develop a hedonic pricing model taking into consideration apartment features and subjective attractiveness using photos and computer vision techniques from the machine learning literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Policy in a Dynamic Search-Matching Model with Heterogeneous Workers and Firms</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/minwage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/minwage/</guid>
      <description>We analyse the consequences of the minimum wage on employment and sorting in a model of the labor market with search frictions, heterogeneous workers and firms, and business cycle fluctuations. This is a joint project with Jeremy Lise and Jean-Marc Robin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Equilibrium and Commuting Costs</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/spatialeq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/spatialeq/</guid>
      <description>This paper explores the connection between commuting costs and local employment dynamics, exploiting a spatial discontinuity introduced by a reform in France in September 2015. The reform, which reduced the cost of public transportation in selected areas of the Paris region without affecting others, provides a unique opportunity to investigate these dynamics. Using a baseline regression framework that only includes geographical units near each other, I find that areas benefitting from the reform saw a 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Income Shocks Along the Business Cycle</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/laborincomeshocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/laborincomeshocks/</guid>
      <description>This paper analyzes the determinants of labor income shocks along the business cycle. My main finding is that sorting between firms and workers is a key component of idiosyncratic risk. Labor income shocks are analyzed through the lenses of a dynamic search-and-matching model, which I estimate using US data. Because of search frictions and mismatches between firms and workers, the laissez-faire equilibrium is not necessarily optimal. My results underline that the government can tame business cycle fluctuations by designing a simple unemployment insurance scheme improving sorting between firms and workers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>