<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HA models on Julien Pascal</title>
    <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/tags/ha-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HA models on Julien Pascal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Julien Pascal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 18:53:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://julienpascal.github.io/tags/ha-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aiyagari Model with Aggregate Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/post/aiyagariaggregateuncertainty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 18:53:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/post/aiyagariaggregateuncertainty/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Bewley-Huggett-Aiyagari-Imohoroğlu economies are the workhorse of modern macroeconomics. In these economies, markets are &amp;ldquo;incomplete&amp;rdquo;. Agents cannot fully insure against risk and decide to self-insure by holding a safe asset to smooth their consumption (see Ljungqvist and Sargent (2018) for a textbook treatment of this topic).
In this post, I consider the model of Aiyagari (1994). While the original model abstracts from aggregate fluctuations, Economists have since developed several techniques to simulate out-of-steady-state dynamics for this class of models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GenBKM Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/post/genbkm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 18:53:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/post/genbkm/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I presented the BKM algorithm , which can used to approximate solutions of macroeconomic models with aggregate uncertainty and heterogeneous agents. This class of models has been been of great interest for Economists for quite a long time. For instance, Aiyagari (1994) already hinted that taking into consideration heterogeneity along the business cycle is both theoretically important and challenging:
 This class of models may also be useful in resolving various asset return puzzles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>