<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WIP on Julien Pascal</title>
    <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/tags/wip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WIP on Julien Pascal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Julien Pascal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://julienpascal.github.io/tags/wip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Policy in a Dynamic Search-Matching Model with Heterogeneous Workers and Firms</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/minwage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/minwage/</guid>
      <description>We analyse the consequences of the minimum wage on employment and sorting in a model of the labor market with search frictions, heterogeneous workers and firms, and business cycle fluctuations. This is a joint project with Jeremy Lise and Jean-Marc Robin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Tax in a Dynamic Search-and-Matching Model</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/taxation_labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:11:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/taxation_labor/</guid>
      <description>We develop a theoretical framework to evaluate the contribution of different payroll tax schedules to business cycle fluctuations. We build and estimate a dynamic search-and-matching model of the labor market featuring heterogeneous workers, aggregate and idiosyncratic shocks and a non-linear payroll tax schedule. We estimate the model on Italian administrative data for the period 1977-2012 and use our estimated framework to quantitatively evaluate how different payroll tax schedules can amplify business cycle shocks for different types of workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Equilibrium and Commuting Costs</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/spatialeq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/spatialeq/</guid>
      <description>I exploit a spatial discontinuity introduced by a French reform in September 2015 to measure the links between commuting costs, employment and location decisions. I find that the reform led to a 2% decrease in the number of unemployed workers registered in the unemployment agency for the municipalities benefiting from the reform. The employment effect is concentrated on long-term unemployed workers. I build a simple spatial search-and-matching to underline the mechanisms at play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor Income Shocks Along the Business Cycle</title>
      <link>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/laborincomeshocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 18:11:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julienpascal.github.io/project/laborincomeshocks/</guid>
      <description>I show that a dynamic search-and-matching model, in which firms and workers are heterogeneous, possesses the mechanisms to replicate some features the distribution of labor income shocks along the business cycle. I solve for the sticky wage process à la Postel-Vinay and Robin (2002) in the model and Lise and Robin (2017) using a variant of the Krusell-Smith algorithm. I estimate the model using the simulated method of moments on US data, including both employment and wage-related moments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>